http://www.stpaulsbarton.co.uk/administration/data-privacy/

St. Pauls Church
Barton
HomeServicesServicesEvening PrayerVideo & AudioVideo & AudioVideoAudioNews & EventsNews & EventsWeekly NewsletterFacebookTwitterInstagramWeatherTea And ChatBible Comes To Life ExhibitionSafeguardingCalendarContact UsChurch MidweekChurch MidweekSmall GroupsYoung PeopleYoung PeopleCrecheLittle RascalsMessy ChurchAbout UsAbout UsFind UsOur ParishPrayerSupporting OthersSupporting OthersToilet TwinningHistoryHistoryVicars Of St PaulsLinks About St. Paul's BartonBuildings ProjectsBarton Village And The Great WarJohn MilneJohn MilneThe ManEarthquake Milne And The Isle Of WightThe ContributionThe BookFinal Resting PlaceThe AnniversaryMore InformationAcknowledgementsLocal ArtworkPhotosPhotosBuildings Project 2014John Milne ThanksgivingPictures From The Past...21st Century IsraelBaptisms, Weddings & FuneralsAdministrationAdministrationCovid-19GivingData PrivacyConsent FormElectoral RollBanns Of Marriage Application FormLinksLone Working PolicySearchSt. Paul's LibrarySt. Paul's LibraryBible Study GuidesBibles And CommentariesCD's - TeachingCDs - MusicChildren's BooksChristian BooksDVDs -Bible TeachingResource BooksTeenage BooksSite MapHouse Of Bishops Declaration
Home > Administration
> Data Privacy
AdministrationCovid-19GivingData PrivacyConsent FormElectoral RollBanns Of Marriage Application FormLinksLone Working PolicySearchSt. Paul's LibrarySite MapHouse Of Bishops Declaration
Data Privacy
DATA PRIVACY NOTICE
The Parochial Church Council (PCC) of
St. Paul’s Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight
1. Your personal data – what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data.  Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession.  The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”).
2. Who are we?
The PCC of St. Paul’s Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight is the data controller (contact details below).  This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
3. How do we process your personal data?
The PCC of St. Paul’s Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight complies with its obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes: -
To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in a particular geographical area as specified in our constitution;
To provide pastoral care to our parishioners and members;
To administer membership records;
To fundraise and promote the interests of the charity;
To manage our employees and volunteers;
To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);
To inform you of news, events, activities and services running at St Paul’s Barton, Portsmouth Diocese and the wider Christian Church;
To operate the St. Paul’s Barton website (www.stpaulsbarton.co.uk) and deliver the services that individuals have requested.
To contact individuals via surveys to conduct research about their opinions of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.
4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about St. Paul’s Barton, Portsmouth Diocese and wider Christian Church events.
Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement;
Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided: -
the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and
there is no disclosure to a third party without consent.
5. Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church.  We will only share your data with third parties outside of the parish with your consent.
6. How long do we keep your personal data?
We keep your personal data for no longer than reasonably necessary and we only retain your data for the following purposes and use the following criteria to determine how long to retain your personal data.  We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide “Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records” which is available from the Church of England website (see footnote1 for link) and on the church website www.stpaulsbarton.co.uk.
Specifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently.
7. Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: -
The right to request a copy of your personal data which the PCC of St. Paul’s Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight holds about you;
The right to request that the PCC of St. Paul’s Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the PCC of St. Paul’s Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight to retain such data;
The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;
The right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable).
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable).
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.
8. Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions.  Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
9. Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the PCC Secretary of St. Paul’s Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight via our church website www.stpaulsbarton.co.uk or on  07947 153 344.
You can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.
1 Details about retention periods can currently be found in the Record Management Guides located on the Church of England website at
https://www.churchofengland.org/more/libraries-and-archives/records-management-guides
Download a copy of this  notice >>
Download a copy of "Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records" >>
Printable VersionPage last updated: 8th March 2020 7:16 PM
Safeguarding          Find Us          Contact Us
Copyright © 2020 St. Paul's Church, Barton, Newport, Isle of Wight
This church website is powered by Church Edit| Privacy Notice
